<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H365922C98EAA4CFBAAC18331CEE8F13E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>94 HJ 58 IH: Ulysses S. Grant Bicentennial Recognition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2021-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 58</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210914">September 14, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the appointment of Ulysses S. Grant to the grade of General of the Armies of the United States.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HDEE652AD3C8F4A4EB0FCDCC7E3E41147"><section id="H423C4D165E2E4A6C88E287987E3B5130" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This joint resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ulysses S. Grant Bicentennial Recognition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC9E33244E5934F7A89717C69E0EC7066"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header><subsection id="HF8B968DFC6244E97B3DF69FED1B6D5BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H842BE8E9F3174D1E85D1834D89D7E7C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On March 3, 1799, Congress created the grade of <quote>General of the Armies of the United States</quote> as the commander of the Army of the United States (5th Congress, Session III, Chap. 48, Section 9).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6275F2D12164925A3302F42696031E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On March 16, 1802, Congress effectively dissolved the grade of General of the Armies of the United States when it passed the Military Peace Establishment Act without reference to the grade (7th Congress, Session I, Chap. 9, Sec. 3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12B879A08F83411EBB99DD497709308B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On July 1, 1843, Ulysses S. Grant graduated from the United States Military Academy at West Point, and, on July 31, 1854, Grant resigned from the Army at the grade of Captain.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD458AAEC09FC4F8DB8072B492A8078FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Following President Abraham Lincoln’s April 15, 1861, proclamation calling for 75,000 volunteers to suppress Confederate forces, Ulysses S. Grant rejoined the Army and helped recruit and train volunteer soldiers for the Union.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF054CAFCF6B6472ABD3A7AA2C264CEDB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Over the course of the American Civil War, Ulysses S. Grant commanded a cumulative total of over 620,000 Union soldiers and achieved major victories including Fort Henry (February 1862), Fort Donelson (February 1862), Shiloh (April 1862), the Vicksburg Campaign (November 1862—July 1863), Chattanooga (November 1863), the Wilderness Campaign (May 1864—June 1864), the Petersburg Campaign (June 1864—April 1865), and the Appomattox Campaign (April 1865).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6ABBA9A5CFE4AD99141DC79E0B2293B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On February 29, 1864, Congress reestablished the grade of <quote>Lieutenant-General of the United States Army</quote> and authorized the President to appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, an officer who was <quote>most distinguished for courage, skill, and ability</quote> (38th Congress, Session I, Chap. 14, Sec. 1); that same day, President Abraham Lincoln nominated Ulysses S. Grant to be Lieutenant-General.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E57C5C54DCA47E583DFB5470B6BD390"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On March 10, 1864, President Abraham Lincoln formally appointed Ulysses S. Grant to the grade of Lieutenant-General of the Army, a position previously held by only George Washington and Winfield Scott, although Scott’s promotion was a brevet appointment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H864496CC1B764908BD602C793DB6815B"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 25, 1866, Congress established the grade of <quote>General of the Army of the United States</quote> (39th Congress, Session I, Chap. 232), and Ulysses S. Grant was appointed, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to General of the Army of the United States for his role in commanding the Union armies during the Civil War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35EE6B697083479FA9B46020374B7DCF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>On March 4, 1869, Ulysses S. Grant was sworn in as the 18th President of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53BA0B63EA0C4C68BAF73FB5D51EB79B"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Throughout his two terms as President, Ulysses S. Grant secured the ratification of the 15th amendment to the Constitution, the creation of the Department of Justice, and the passage and implementation of the Civil Rights Act of 1875. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD411308579C04C7D80306990B2F0D2C8"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On October 11, 1976, Congress enacted <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/479">Public Law 94–479</external-xref>, which re-established the grade of <quote>General of the Armies of the United States</quote> to posthumously request the appointment of George Washington to General of the Armies of the United States and made clear that this grade has <quote>precedence over all other grades of the Army, past or present</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H485E176321DE47CBAE5D148B4974A8AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this joint resolution is to—</text><paragraph id="HA743D6DDEFC44D9C905638B17BC154F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honor Ulysses S. Grant for his efforts and leadership in defending the union of the United States of America;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4B671AA19604EF4867E32EB6DA9FBA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognize that the military victories achieved under the command of Ulysses S. Grant were integral to the preservation of the United States of America; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFAEDD82980E4DF2840ABC8BA35E9D18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirm that Ulysses S. Grant is among the most influential military commanders in the history of the United States of America.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0A507E8928234D2FB68D94C3099ADC71"><enum>3.</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President is authorized and requested to appoint Ulysses S. Grant posthumously to the grade of General of the Armies of the United States, such appointment to take effect on April 27, 2022.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

